Nnaemeka Benjamin Obioha

Bridgeland Road, Victoria Dock, E16 United Kingdom 07475738950

nnaemeka.obioha@gmail.com

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A pragmatic Front End Developer with a keen eye for detail and eagerness to provide great user experience. Takes the initiative in problem solving situations and thrives on working with JavaScript based web technologies like React.js, Redux, Webpack and Node.js, to deliver projects that meet modern design, performance and accessibility best practices. Communicates clearly and possesses a strong team ethic.

KEY AWARDS

- Participated in the University of Greenwich 2018 Business Enterprise Challenge and the 2019 GRE Start-up bootcamp.
- Awarded a tier 1 Graduate Entrepreneur visa in the United Kingdom.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer, Ugarsoft Nigeria Ltd (cir 40)

02/2018 - 03/2019

Privately held: ICT consulting and application development. Responsible to: Project Manager

- Responsible for developing user and administrative dashboard views using React/Redux and Bootstrap framework for Xend.ng digital wallet application.
- Successfully coached two new interns in my department.
- Successfully created intelligent user interfaces and mock-ups in Adobe XD.
- Performed research into new tools and technologies for both existing and future projects.

Front End Developer, University of Greenwich Bright Agency (cir 20)

11/2017 - 01/2018

 $\textbf{Privately held:} \ \textbf{ICT} \ consulting \ and \ application \ development. \ \textbf{Responsible to:} \ Project \ Supervisor$

- Made some contributions to a client project.
- Created a weather hybrid mobile app with Ionic 3 and Angular 4. (WeatherUp on android play store)

Casual Engineer, Line Management Group UK (cir 500)

03/2017 - 05/2018

Privately held: Workspace intelligence solutions. Responsible to: Line Manager

- Carried out hardware maintenance on trading desks.
- Successfully carried out over 300 workstation moves.
- Provided workstation support and maintenance for staff at Barclays Bank Investment Capital.

Front End Developer, Ugarsoft Nigeria Ltd (cir 10)

01/2016 - 01/2017

Privately held: ICT consulting and application development. Responsible to: Founder

 Created mock-ups, designed and developed multiple client websites with bootstrap framework on custom WordPress and Drupal themes.

Front End Developer, Lloydant Business Services Nigeria (cir 20)

09/2015 - 12/2015

Privately held: Educational Technology solutions and ICT consulting services Responsible to: CTO

- Support team members by building user interfaces in HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and bootstrap 3 for in house projects.
- Attended client meetings and reported desires to line manager.

Web Design, Campus Portal Nigeria (cir 5)

01/2014 - 08/2015

Privately held: Educational Blog Responsible to: Founder

- Built websites with WordPress CMS.
- Built client mock-ups with adobe illustrator then used WordPress plugins to build the finished version.
- Support content creation and monitor user engagement analytics.

EDUCATION

University of Greenwich United Kingdom

2017 - 2018

First Class in M.Sc. Mechanical and Manufacturing Engineering

University of Nigeria Nsukka

2008 - 2013

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering

Doyen Academy Enugu, Nigeria

2007 – 2008

Cambridge A-Levels

Federal Government College, Enugu

2001 - 2007

• West Africa Senior School Certificate

SKILLS

- Proficient in HTML5/CSS3 and JavaScript frameworks like Vue.js and React.js.
- Proficient in Nodejs, MongoDB, ES6, Restful APIs, NPM, Webpack, Docker and Git.
- Experient in UI creation tools like Adobe XD, Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Proficient in word and data processing software like Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint.

MEMBERSHIP

- United Kingdom Black Technology community (UKBT) member.
- Member of Society of Petroleum Engineers (SPE No. 3499375).

PORTFOLIO

- www.benobioha.me
- www.github.com/ben4code

INTERESTS

- Interests include networking at events, listening to audiobooks and a Marvel Cinematic Universe fan
- Active volunteer for kiddiesdom, a child safety awareness NGO in Nigeria.

ADDIONAL INFORMATION

- · Reference available upon request.
- Flexible to travel regionally, nationally and work away from home.